Andrew Messier

Senior Software Engineer / Web Developer (CSM)

andrewmessier.com

Charlotte, NC 28203 andrewgmessier@gmail.com (704) 743-6265 linkedin.com/in/andrewgmessier stackoverflow.com/cv/andrewmessier github.com/messman

Software engineer with over five years of professional web and API development knowledge.

Experienced in building web applications including design/UI, UX, APIs, and data processing and management. **Seeking new challenges in web development**: contributing to a driven team to create powerful applications that empower users and solve complex problems; assisting in business strategy and direction.

Knowledge

JavaScript & TypeScript; React & Redux; Node.js, npm, Babel, Webpack, & Gulp; jQuery & Bootstrap; HTML5 & CSS/SCSS; git & VSTS; VS Code & Visual Studio; ASP.NET Core; Docker; SSMS & SQL

Experience

Senior Software Developer, Jackrabbit Technologies - Huntersville, NC

October 2019 - Present

(Previously: .NET Front End Web Developer, August 2018 – October 2019)

- Heads development team Scrum meetings on a stand-in basis as a Certified Scrum Master.
- Leads technical debt epics on behalf of the Product Team and Engineering Director.
- Collaborates remotely with Product Analysts, QA, designers, and other developers to build web application features in Agile Sprints.
- Assists in the modernization and organization of the codebase by working with other developers to shift the team to TypeScript and React.

Software Engineer, LEAD Technologies, Inc. - Charlotte, NC

June 2015 - July 2018

(Previously: Software Engineering Intern, Summers of 2013 and 2014)

- Responsible for multiple customer-facing single-page JavaScript web applications of a toolkit; optimization skills reduced load times by 50%-75%.
- Built web services for multiple platforms to bridge web applications with document processing.
- Refined HTML5 Canvas event-update-rendering patterns to significantly increase graphical responsiveness.
- Updated team's legacy code to standard builds and languages, decreasing turnaround time for bugs.

Projects

quick-tides - github.com/messman/quick-tides

2017 - Present

A mobile web app to pull NOAA data for the beach town of Wells, Maine so residents (like my parents) and their renters can have simple, fast, and reliable access to information about the weather and tides.

- Uses React for componentized UI and SCSS for organized design.
- Leverages TypeScript for compile-time type checking of props between components.
- Uses Docker and an Nginx proxy to connect the front-end application and express.js back-end data service.

More projects at andrewmessier.com.

Education

University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill, NC

Class of 2015

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science – Graduation With Distinction (3.70)

- Led classes, tutored, and created assignments as an assistant for an introductory web programming course.
- Managed student-employees and assisted patrons as an on-campus recreation center building supervisor.